Finding Aid to Framed Items from the Collections of The Bancroft Library
The Bancroft Library
- Individual Framed Items
  - Hills near Salinas [Calif.], [19--?]; Unknown; BANC PIC 1979.018--D; 1 painting paper mounted on board: watercolor; 37.9 x 55.6 cm. Handwritten title (verso): Hills near Salinas. Manufacturer's stamp (verso): Whatman (extra hard sized drawing paper on board).
    Landscapes (Representations) -- California; Watercolors
  - [Bacon Art and Library Building, University of California, Berkeley], [ca. 1900]; Unknown; BANC PIC 1979.025--FR; 1 painting on prepared paper mounted on board: oil; visible image 27.9 x 41.5 cm.
    View of building through trees with meadow in foreground.
    Oil paintings; Bacon Hall (Berkeley, Calif.) -- Pictorial works; University of California (1868-1952) -- Buildings -- Pictorial works
  - The Sonnet: Anima, April 27, 1880; Rossetti, Dante Gabriel; Sharp, William; BANC PIC 1979.056--FR; 1 print: etching; visible image 10 x 16.4 cm. Printed title (UL): Anima. Printed (LL): D. G. Rossetti pro matre fecit Apr: 27. 1880. Handwritten (verso): To W. B. Scott / with friendly regards from / William Sharp / 9:12:'82 / (mounted on lower border, trimmed from mat board): proof on India paper / William Sharp. Signatures and handwriting appear to be the same on both inscriptions.
    This is the decorated copy Rossetti made of the "Introductory Sonnet" to the 1881 edition of "The House of Life." The design was executed as a present for his mother on her eightieth birthday (27 April 1880). It is supposed to have been copied into David Main's edition of "A Treasury of English Sonnets," which Rossetti gave to his mother as a present.
    The lost original design is known from two printed copies made from it, one of which was published as the frontispiece to William Sharp's "Dante Gabriel Rossetti. A Record and a Study" (1882). It is possible that this is the original proof for Sharp's frontispiece. (see: The Complete Writings and Pictures of Dante Gabriel Rossetti - http://www.iath.virginia.edu/rossetti/)
    Winged female figure, her head is crowned with a laurel wreath, holding a lyre and hourglass suspended above a rose bower surrounding the sonnet.
    Allegories; Proofs
  - The Berkeley Hills, Cal., 1915; Breuer, Henry Joseph; BANC PIC 1979.076--FR; 1 painting on board: oil; visible image 12 x 17 cm. Painted initials and date (LL): H. J. B. 15. Handwritten (verso): The Berkeley Hills, Cal. (In artist's hand) / Henry J. Breuer / born Phil 1860 / died cal - 1932 / reference fieldings [dictionary of artists] / Malletts [Independent?] / etc.
    Oil paintings; Berkeley (Calif.) -- Pictorial works
  - [Marion Ward, Louise Ward & Annie Mailliard], [18--?]; Storrow, Rebecca J.; BANC PIC 1980.027--FR; 1 painting on paper: oil; visible image 11.5 x 10.5 cm, dome top frame. Handwritten (UC verso): Marion Ward / Louisa Crawford nee Ward / Annie Mailliard " " [nee Ward] / painted by Miss Hall / this miniature painted by / Rebecca J. Storrow.
    Portrait group of adolescent male with two little girls in his lap. The girls hold bouquets of roses and morning glories.
    Oil paintings; Ward family -- Pictorial works; Group portraits
  - [Portrait of John Augustus Sutter], c1852; Pierce, J.H.; Butler, B. F.; Johnson, W.H.; BANC PIC 1980.043--FR; 1 print: lithograph; 26.7 x 20.5 cm. Printed signature (LC): J. A. Sutter. Printed (LL): Lith. of B. F. Butler; (LR): Drawn on stone by J. H. Peirce from a portrait by S. W. Shaw; (LC): Published by Peirce & Johnson, San Francisco, California 1852 / entered according to act of Congress in the year 1852 by J. H. Peirce and W. H. Johnson [...] Additional descriptive information on label (verso).
    Bust portrait of owner of Sutter's Mill, site of gold discovery in January 1848.
    Portraits; Lithographs; Sutter, John Augustus, -- 1803-1880 -- Portraits
  - [California Panorama], 1860; Robinson, Charles Dorman; BANC PIC 1980.047a-n--FR; 1 composite image (9 panels stitched together) on fabric: distemper; 23 x 506 cm.
    Content/DescriptionScenes (L to R): 1. Bay scene, 2. New Almaden Mining area 3. View of San Jose (after print by Levi Goodrich, publ. Britton & Rey 1858), 4. Panorama of San Francisco from Alcatraz to Meiggs Wharf to Valley (from print after original by C.B. Gifford), 5. Freeman's Express Steamship and Antelope docking at wharf (Hutching's California Magazine, July 1859, p. 5), 6. Steamer on the bay of San Francisco (Hutching's California Magazine, July 1859, p. 9), 7. [Napa Valley?], 8. California Geyser Springs scene (Hutching's California Magazine, January 1860, p. 267), 9. View of Benicia (Hutching's California Magazine, July 1859, p. 10).
  - [Cattle drove at Mission Dolores, Calif.], [ca. 1880]; Englan, Thomas; BANC PIC 1981.024--FR; 1 painting: oil; visible image 40 x 81.3 cm. Signature (LR): Thos. Englan. Handwritten (verso): # 73.
    Church buildings with vaqueros on horseback in foreground driving cattle.
    Oil paintings; Spanish mission buildings -- California -- San Francisco -- Pictorial works; San Francisco de Asis Mission (San Francisco, Calif.) -- Pictorial works; Cattle -- California -- San Francisco -- Pictorial works
  - [San Francisco harbor, Calif.], [ca. 1853-1855]; Meyers, William Henry; BANC PIC 1981.029--FR; 1 painting on paper: watercolor and pencil; visible image 15.9 x 61 cm. Handwritten title (LC). Identification of landmarks handwritten on left edge and in image. Label with biographical information on verso.
    View of bay and city of San Francisco looking from Golden Gate. Noted landmarks include Blossom Rock, signal staff (Telegraph Hill), Meigg's Warf, North Beach, and the resevoir. Several masted ships, sailboats, and a steamship on the water.
    Watercolors; San Francisco Bay (Calif.) -- Pictorial works; Blossom Rock, San Francisco Bay -- Pictorial works
  - [The Oakland Estuary], [ca. 1920]; Jörgensen, Christian; BANC PIC 1981.033--FR; 1 painting on paper: watercolor; visible image 26.6 x 36.1 cm. Handwritten note regarding attribution attached to verso.
    Empty hull of ship on shore of waterway in foreground; Oakland City Hall and twin towers of the Hotel Oakland visible in distance.
    Hotel Oakland (Oakland, Calif.) -- Pictorial works; Oakland City Hall (Oakland, Calif.) -- Pictorial works; Oakland (Calif.) -- Pictorial works; Shipping -- California -- Oakland -- Pictorial works
  - [Portrait of Frederick W. Goudy, American type designer], [19--?]; Unknown; BANC PIC 1981.100--FR; 1 photograph on paper: photogravure; visible image 23.5 x 17.6 cm. Handwritten title (LR). Handwritten (verso): F. W. Goudy / Am. typedesigner / in his prime. / [signed - illegible].
    Half length portrait.
    Printers -- New York (State) -- New York -- Portraits; Goudy, Frederic W. -- (Frederic William), -- 1865-1947 -- Portraits; Photogravures
  - [Charles A. Murdock in his printing office], [1970]; Mahoney, J. Carroll; BANC PIC 1981.101--FR; 1 photographic print: b&w; 34.2 x 15.9 cm. Provenance information handwritten (on verso).
    Full length portrait of man with typesetter's desk behind him.
    Printers -- California -- San Francisco Bay Area -- Photographs; Murdock, Charles A. -- (Charles Albert), -- 1841-1928 -- Portraits
  - [Cape Disappointment], [1881?]; Denny, Gideon Jacques; BANC PIC 1981.143--FR; 1 painting on canvas: oil; 39 x 77 cm. 36.5 x 74.5 cm., visible image Signature (LL): G.J. Denny [81?]. Acquisition information on label (verso). oil on canvas
    View of a coastline from the sea, presumably Cape Disappointment in Washington State, showing a steamship in the center, a buoy in the foreground, and cliffs, a lighthouse, and harbor to the right.
    Oil paintings; Disappointment, Cape (Wash.) -- Pictorial works; Seascapes
  - Grass Valley [Calif.], [ca. 1930]; Boynton, Ray; BANC PIC 1981.162--FR; 1 drawing: pastel; visible image 20.8 x 28.1 cm. Handwritten title (LL): Grass Valley. Explanatory sheet on verso.
    View of a corner of the street: historic Mother Load Building at the left; trees and telephone pole at center and right.
    Drawings; Pastels (Visual works); Grass Valley (Calif.) -- Pictorial works
  - [Portrait of C. Hart Merriam], [not after 1942]; Unknown; BANC PIC 1981.164--FR; 1 painting: oil; 112 x 92 cm.
    Oil paintings; Merriam, C. Hart -- (Clinton Hart), -- 1855-1942 -- Portraits
  - [Daniel Boone], 1863; Nehlig, Victor; BANC PIC 1982.028--FR; 1 painting on panel: oil; visible image 19.2 x 15.5 cm. Painted signature and date (LR): V. Nehlig 1863. Label from Kennedy Galleries New York and biographical information attached to verso.
    Image of Daniel Boone (1734-1820) seated in the woods with a long rifle, looking over his shoulder.
    Oil paintings; Boone, Daniel, -- 1734-1820 -- Portraits
  - Bird's eye view of Marysville and Yuba City, Cal[ifornia] and surrounding country., 1888; W.W. Elliott Lithographers; Cook, C. P.; BANC PIC 1982.030--E; 1 print: lithograph; sheet 59.5 x 82 cm. Printed title (LC). Printed initials (LR in image): FW. Printed (LR in image): Lith. W.W. Elliott. S.F. sketched by C.P. Cook, 1888; (LC below title): Compliments of the Marysville Daily and Weekly Democrat. Printed explanatory key to locations in central image (LR and LL). Printed articles on Yuba and Sutter Counties (at bottom).
    Content/DescriptionLarge central image is overview of cities, Yuba and Feather Rivers and distant hills, showing buildings and farms. Marginal images of prominent businesses, public buildings and residences include M.C. Clark residence; office of Daily and Weekly Democrat; C. Weeman residence; public school; California Brewery; U.S. Hotel; St. Joseph's Church; Notre Dame College; Sutter County Court House; Yuba County Court House; Marysville Winery; Presbyterian Church; Golden Eagle Hotel; Peri block with White, Copley & Cu[?]s [store], Peri's Confectionery, and Hochstadter & Bro. clothing store; Windsor House; M.T. Featherly residence; R.C. Kells residence, S.C. Deaner residence.
    Bird's-eye views; Lithographs; Marysville (Calif.) -- Aerial views; Yuba City (Calif.) -- Aerial views; Marysville (Calif.) -- Pictorial works
  - [Nevada Falls, Yosemite], 1894; Hill, Thomas, Virgil Troyon; BANC PIC 1982.032--FR; 1 painting on board: oil; visible image 44.6 x 29.5 cm. Painted signature and date (LR): T. Hill 94.
    View of waterfall in Yosemite National Park, Calif. with figure on river bank in foreground.
    Oil paintings; Yosemite National Park (Calif.) -- Pictorial works
  - Mose in California: Set-to with a Bear., c1849; Robinson, H. R.; BANC PIC 1982.082--C; 1 print: lithograph, hand colored; image 39 x 28 cm, on mount 40.5 x 29.5 cm. Printed title (LL). Printed (LL): Lith & Pub. by H. R. Robinson; Printed (LC): Entered according to Act of Congress; A.D. 1849 by H. R. Robinson... Printed (LR): 31 Park Row N.Y.
    Humorous scene of a miner intending to teach a bear a lesson. Miner with dagger at hip boxing bear. Tree and barrel labeled GOLD in left background. Monkey sitting on barrel holding tree branch. Jacket, hat, shovel, pix axe, and "16 1/2 lbs" gold nugget at base of barrel.
    Lithographs -- Hand-colored; Caricatures -- Hand-colored; Bears -- Pictorial works; Miners -- California -- Pictorial works
  - [California sugar refinery, San Francisco], [ca. 1890?]; Taber, I. W. (Isaiah West); BANC PIC 1982.087--D; 1 photograph: albumen; 21.8 x 52.8 cm. Printed (LR): Taber Photo, S.F. Printed title (LC): California Sugar Refinery. The mount bears the company address, and names various officers (all of the Spreckels family).
    View of the Spreckels Sugar Company refinery buildings looking from the San Francisco Bay, with a train at left and masted ships at right.
    Spreckels Sugar Company -- Pictorial works; Sugar factories -- California -- San Francisco -- Photographs; Albumen prints
  - [Landscape Study], [188-?]; Keith, William; BANC PIC 1983.122:001--FR; 1 painting on panel (cigar box lid); oil; visible image 12.3 x 23.1 cm. Signature (LL): W. Keith. Stamp on panel (verso, cigar lid): La Alteza de Habana.
    Possibly a prepatory sketch for a larger painting done by Keith of the Berkeley hills with Mt. Tamalpias in distance at one time held by the Fine Arts Museums of San Francisco.
    Open field with cows and trees at left and hills in the distance.
  - [Self portrait of Xavier Martinez], [ca. 1912]; Martinez, Xavier; BANC PIC 1983.203--FR; 1 painting: oil on academy board; visible image 29.5 x 24.4. Insignia[?] (LL). Handwritten (verso): To Haig - / from Marty. Handwritten note (verso): Xavier Martinez / (self portrait) / presented to Haig Patigian / by the artist in October, 1912. Exhibition label with biographical information on verso.
    Bust (oil sketch) portrait of artist Xavier Martinez (1869-1943).
    Oil paintings; Self-Portraits; Martinez, Xavier, -- 1869-1943 -- Portraits
  - [Kaiser prototype for oceanliner with plane launch], [ca. 1930-1940]; Kaiser Industries Corporation; BANC PIC 1983.021.01--FR; 1 painting: oil; 61 x 92 cm. Painted initials (LR): H [I?] N
    Ultra-modern oceanliner with plane launch seen at sea; view of coast in the distance. Prototype vessel made for the Kaiser Corporation.
    Oil paintings; Vessels
  - Near Almaden [sic - titled on verso], [ca. 1900?]; Hill, Thomas; BANC PIC 1984.040--FR; 1 painting on canvas: oil; 8 1/4 x 13 1/4 in.
    Oil paintings; Landscapes (Representations) -- California; New Almaden (Calif.) -- Pictorial works
  - [Dr. Horatio Stebbins], 1895; Withrow, Evelyn; BANC PIC 1984.109--FR; 1 painting: oil; 93 x 77.8 cm. Painted signature (LR): Eva Withrow / S.F. / '95.
    Half length portrait of Stebbins, a Unitarian minister and Regent, University of California.
    Oil paintings; Stebbins, Horatio, -- 1821-1902 -- Pictorial works
  - [Quillote, the home of Kate Douglas Wiggin, Maine], [19--?]; Vinton, Frederic P.; BANC PIC 1984.116--FR; 1 painting on panel: oil; visible image 24.4 x 34.6 cm. Label (LR verso): sketched of Quillote / by Frederic P. Vinton of Boston. Windsor & Newton manufacture's label on verso, additional labels and info on verso.
    House seen through trees.
    Oil paintings; Maine -- Pictorial works
  - [El Capitan and river, Yosemite Valley, Calif.], [ca. 1915]; Worden, Willard E.; BANC PIC 1984.133:1--FR; 1 photograph: b&w; visible image 23 x 16.7 cm. Embossed copyright and signature (LR): © Worden / S.F. Label on verso for Worden's Stockton St. studio noting P.P.I.E. highest award 1915.
    View across river with El Capitan reflected in the water and visible in the distance.
    Yosemite National Park (Calif.) -- Pictorial works
  - Laguna Rancho, Residence of Geo. W. Burbank, Tomales Tp. Marin Co. Cal., [188-]; Moore, E.S.; Britton & Rey; Moore & DePue; BANC PIC 1984.137--FR; 1 print: lithograph; visible image 37.4 x 53.3 cm. Printed signature (LL in image): E.S. Moore Del. Printed title (LC). Printed (LL): Moore & DePue, Pub. S.F.; (LR): Britton & Rey, Lith. S.F.
    Main image of Victorian house with circular drive surrounded by gated pastures, orchards, farm buildings and rolling hills with a pond in the foreground. Two marginal images show a lake and woods. The property was located along the banks of the Estero San Antonio Laguna. George Walton Burbank (1929-1901) was a leading figure in Tomales Township. He came to California in 1854 and after a short time in the gold fields became a farmer. He was followed to California by his brother Luther Burbank, a noted horticulturist.
  - View of Downieville, Forks of the North Yuba River, [1851?]; O'Grady, William H.; Justh, Quirot & Co.; Langton, Samuel W.; BANC PIC 1985.071--FR; 1 print (pictorial lettersheet): b&w, lithograph; visible image 26.5 x 36.7 cm. Printed (LL): Del. W. H. O-Grady; (LR): lith. by Justh, Quirot & Co. Calif.a St. corner Montgomery, San - Francisco; (LL): view of Downieville, Forks of North Yuba River. / Published and sold by Samuel W. Langton of Langton's Express Downieville, California. Acquisition info on label on verso.
    View depicts the city of Downieville shortly after it was founded in 1849 showing diversion structures and water wheels along river.
    Lithographs; Pictorial lettersheets; Downieville (Calif.) -- Pictorial works
  - [Gelett Burgess], [1919]; Flagg, James Montgomery; BANC PIC 1985.094--FR; 1 drawing: charcoal; visible image 34.4 x 25.5 cm. Handwritten title and signature (LL): Gelett Burgess / James Montgomery Flagg. Dated 1919 on verso.
    Three-quarter profile portrait head of Burgess (1866-1951), author of "The Purple Cow."
    Portraits; Charcoal drawings; Burgess, Gelett, -- 1866-1951 -- Portraits
  - [Self-portrait as Indian], [1910]; Martinez, Xavier; BANC PIC 1986.004--FR; 1 drawing: silverpoint; visible image 21 x 8.2 cm. Handwritten note on verso indicates that the portrait of Xavier Martinez was made for one of his students at California College of Arts and Crafts, Ms. Lucy V. Pierce, in 1910.
    Full length profile portrait of the artist wearing a feather headdress and moccasins, wrapped in a blanket.
    Self-Portraits; Martinez, Xavier, -- 1869-1943 -- Portraits; Silverpoint drawings
  - [Mission San Luis Rey de Espana], [1880]; Ford, Henry Chapman; BANC PIC 1986.031--FR; 1 painting on paper: watercolor; visible image 43 x 27.8 cm. Painted signature (LL): H. C. Ford.
    View of Mission yard showing ruined building and dome, bell tower and three crosses marking burial sites.
    Spanish mission buildings -- California -- Pictorial works; Watercolors; San Luis Rey Mission (Calif.) -- Pictorial works
  - On the Coast of California, [18--]; F. Gleason; BANC PIC 1987.003--FR; 1 print on textured paper: chromolithograph; visible image 37.8 x 53.2 cm. Printed title (LL in image). Date and attribution from label on verso.
    Tropical coastal scene with palm trees and huts with thatched roofs; snow-covered cone-shaped peak in distance. Road winding along coast with pedestrians and pack horses, ships in distant harbor.
    Chromolithographs; Coasts -- California -- Pictorial works; Pacific Coast (Calif.) -- Pictorial works
  - [James D. Hart], [197-?]; Knight, George; BANC PIC 1987.013--FR; 1 photograph: b&w; visible image 24 x 16.8 cm.
    Bust portrait of former Director of The Bancroft Library.
    Portraits; Hart, James David, -- 1911- -- Portraits
  - [Lumber schooner on the Oakland Estuary, Calif.], 1897; Jörgensen, Christian; BANC PIC 1987.015--FR; 1 painting on paper: ink wash; visible image 37 x 22.2 cm. Painted signature (LR): Chris Jorgensen. 97.
    Four masted ship on shore seen from below bow with lumber beneath the gangplank.
    Saratoga (Calif.) -- Pictorial works; Lumber trade -- California -- Pictorial works; Ink painting
  - Salt Lake City [Utah]., 1887; S.W. Darke & Company; BANC PIC 1987.034--E; 1 print: lithograph; sheet 60 x 90 cm. Printed title (LC). Printed (LR): Gast--St. L[ouis] & N.Y. [Possibly L. Gast & Bros., but probably August Gast & Co.]; (LL): Entered according to act of Congress in the year 1887, by S.W. Darke & Co. Salt Lake City, in the office of the Librarian of Congress at Washington, D.C.
    Bird's eye view of city with insets showing City Hall and Fort Douglas.
    Bird's-eye views; Lithographs; Salt Lake City (Utah) -- Pictorial works; Fort Douglas (Utah) -- Pictorial works; Cityscapes -- Utah -- Salt Lake City
  - [Western scene with Indian camp], [ca. 1865]; Cleenewerck, Henry; BANC PIC 1987.046--FR; 1 painting: oil; visible image 32 x 53 cm. Painted signature (LR): Henry Cleenewerck. Title and date from label on verso.
    Campsite with three tipis (teepees, tepees) along river's edge. Indians on horseback and around campfire. Mountains and snow-covered peaks in distance.
    Oil paintings; Landscapes; West (U.S.) -- Pictorial works; Indians of North America -- West (U.S.) -- Pictorial works
  - [Self portrait of Henry Raschen], 1882; Raschen, Henry; BANC PIC 1987.047--FR; 1 painting: oil; visible image 30.3 x 24.5 cm. Painted signature (LR): H. Raschen / 1882.
    Bust-length portrait done in the old master's style.
    Oil paintings; Self-Portraits; Raschen, Henry, -- 1856-1937 -- Selfportraits
  - [Victorian Residence, San Francisco, Calif.], [ca. 1870]; Unknown; BANC PIC 1987.048--FR; 1 painting: oil; visible image 31 x 42.2 cm.
    Two story Italianate building in the Rincon Hill area with arched windows, an iron porch, and trained vines on trellises. The dwelling is surrounded by a garden and iron fence, with a distant view of San Francisco.
    Oil paintings; Dwellings -- California -- San Francisco -- Pictorial works; San Francisco (Calif.) -- Buildings, structures, etc. -- Pictorial works
  - The Tuolumne River, [1970-1987]; Briggs, Don; BANC PIC 1987.072--FR; 1 photograph: color; 33.6 x 51 cm. Handwritten title and signature (verso): The Tuolumne River / by / Don Briggs.
    Aerial view of the Tuolumne River and surrounding hills.
    Water resources development -- California -- Environmental aspects -- Photographs; Tuolumne River (Calif.) -- Pictorial works
  - [Guilio Silva's home in Lagunitas, Marin County, Calif.], [1930]; Silva, Giulio; BANC PIC 1987.107--FR; 1 painting on cardboard: oil; 17.5 x 22.7 cm. Handwritten signature (LR): G. Silva [faded]. Handwritten (verso): To my dear friends / Elysabeth and Albert El[lu?]s / Happy Christmas / 1930 / Giulo Silva.
    Apparently a view of Silva's house in Lagunitas, Marin County, California as seen through the trees.
    Oil paintings; California -- Pictorial works
  - Panoramic View of Stockton. Cal. Taken July 4th, 1895, c1895; Dakin Publishing Co.; BANC PIC 1988.020--FR; 1 photographic montage (8 images); visible image 33 x 249.7 cm. Handwritten and printed title (LC). Handwritten and printed (LC below title): from roof of Golden Gate and Union Mills by / Dakin Publishing Company. / 320 Sansome Street. San Francisco. Printed Label (LR): Copyrighted 1895 by / Dakin Publishing Co. / 320 Sansome St., San Francisco.
    Broad view from beyond Weber Avenue to Mormon Channel. Includes two marginal images of Golden Gate and Union Flour Mill, and San Joaquin County Court House. Points of interest and local businesses are noted along lower margin, including: Stockton Milling Co. and Crown Flour Mill warehouse, Terminal of SF and SJ VRR and A + SJ lines, Stockton Channel, Regata, State Insane Aylum, Pacific Tannery, Weber buildings, Churches, Yosemite Theater, California Paper Mills, and Stockton Woolen Mills. Three paddlewheel steamships and crowds along dock edge and shore.
  - [Old Bale Mill in St. Helena, California], [ca. 1936?]; Ellis, Alice; BANC PIC 1988.033:1--FR; 1 print: linoleum block; visible image 21.5 x 26.5 cm. Handwritten title (LL): Bail [sic] Mill. Handwritten signature (LR): Alice Ellis.
    View of mill through trees.
    Gristmills -- California -- Saint Helena -- Photographs; Saint Helena (Calif.) -- Pictorial works; Linocuts
  - [Sailing ships at anchor in Richardson Bay, Calif.], [not after 1936]; Coulter, William A.; BANC PIC 1988.099--FR; 1 painting: oil; visible image 50 x 70.4 cm. Painted signature (LR): W. A. Coulter.
    View of bay with several masted ships, a steam boat, and tug boat. Mt.Tamalpias in distance.
    Oil paintings; Richardson Bay (Calif.) -- Pictorial works; Ships -- Pictorial works; Marines (Visual works) -- California -- San Francisco Bay
  - [Walpi Pueblo landscape, Arizona], [ca. 1930]; Martinez, Xavier; BANC PIC 1989.006--FR; 1 painting on board: oil; visible image 39.1 x 44.5 cm. Signature (monogram) (LL): XM. Some provenance information on verso.
    Southwestern mountain landscape showing Hopi pueblo.
    Oil paintings; Landscapes (Representations) -- Arizona; Walpi Pueblo (Ariz.) -- Pictorial works; Arizona -- Pictorial works; Hopi Indians -- Dwellings -- Arizona -- Walpi -- Pictorial works